USMAN ABDULLAHI

CAREER OVERVIEW

Hello, my name is **Usman Abdullahi**. I am a front-end developer. I primarily focus on writing clean, elegant, and efficient code. I am proficient in HTML, CSS, JavaScript and Frameworks (e.g React). I also review existing code and can consult with you on how to improve it. Over the past two (2) years, I have primarily worked for companies that specialize in enterprise web applications.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Front-end Developer (Trainee) 10/2022 to 12/2022 Codevillage LLC – Ilorin, Nigeria

• Turn design pages and specific components into HTML, CSS and JavaScript • Developed and maintained legacy applications • Analyzed UI/UX design for responsive layout for improved usability • Installing windows, software, applications, antivirus, patches and all developers tools needed for every PC in the company

• Freelance Front-End Developer | Fiverr 03/2023 to current

 Worked in a team environment with React, transformed complex concepts into simple, elegant, and approachable experiences, services, and products● Worked closely with business leaders, graphic designers, software engineers, and QA resources through the complete systems development life cycle ● Analyzed UI/UX design for responsive layout for improved usability● Collaborated with other virtual Co-workers

SELECTED PROJECTS

Project: KosmosHR Employee Management System

As a key contributor to the KosmosHR project, I played a pivotal role in the development and enhancement of Frontend development. The system aimed to streamline and optimize human resource processes, providing comprehensive solutions for employee data management, performance tracking, and overall workforce efficiency.

This experience honed my skills in collaborative development, user-centric design, and the implementation of scalable solutions.

Project: Web Optimisation (Webopt)

WebOpt empowers students to effortlessly create professional websites for their businesses, akin to Shopify. Streamlining the website-building process, it provides intuitive tools for design, customization, and e-commerce functionality. By offering a user-friendly platform, WebOpt equips students with the digital presence needed to showcase and grow their entrepreneurial ventures seamlessly.

• Project: Abdullahi-fawn.vercel.app

Developed a dynamic personal portfolio website using Next.js and Tailwind CSS, showcasing a seamless blend of design and functionality. This online platform encapsulates comprehensive information about my professional experience, skills, and personality, creating an engaging and informative user experience.

CONTACT

Address: Ilorin, Gaa-Akanbi, 240103 Kwara State, Nigeria

Phone: +234 9135 619 423

Email:

uthmanabdullahi2020@gmail.com

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Markup Languages: HTML, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, TypeScript
- Liberaries & Frameworks:

Tailwind-css, Reactjs, Nextjs, Reduxtoolkit

Tools & Platforms: Git, Github,
 Netlify, Vercel, Slack, Discord, Notion,
 Figma.

EDUCATION

Federal University of Ilorin (Unilorin)

Bachelor of science in Information Technology

2021 - current

CERTIFICATIONS

- Frontend Development
 Certification, CodeVillage LLC
- Responsive Web Design
 Certification, FreeCodeCamp
- Frontend Development Libraries
 Certification, FreeCodeCamp